

Software DeveloperJustin Gates

Contact info

phone: 208-695-4231 justingates.dev@gmail.com

JUSTIN.PORTFOLIO.COM

https://github.com/JustinLGates https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-l-gates

Skills

Coding Languages

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- C#
- Java
- SQL
- Python
- PHP

Frameworks / Systems:

- Vue.Js
- Bootstrap
- Node.Js
- MongoDb
- Scrum
- MVC pattern
- Git
- Github
- android studio
- auth0
- Heroku
- Unity
- Visual studio code

Education

CodeWorks April-July 2020

Certificates of completion

• Full Stack web July 2020

SoloLearn 2018 - 2020

Certificate of completion

- HTML Sep 2018
- JavaScript Sep 2018
- CSS Oct 2018
- C# Jan 2020
- Java April 2019
- SQL Oct- 2018
- Python Sep 2018
- PHP Oct 2018

Profile

Experienced in building full stack web applications using various Languages and frameworks using the solid principals of object oriented programming and the MVC design pattern . Passionate about problem solving and learning new things. 10 Years of experience leading others in a fast paced environment.

Experience

Papa Murphy's Store Manager- May 2009 - April 2020

- Primed 6 managers for several locations on leadership, scheduling, forecasting sales, inventory control and labor control.
- Hired ,trained and coached 100+ staff members on customer service, food safety and operational standards.
- Exceeded expectations controlling labor and food by forecasting sales accurately and holding team members accountable.
- Often ranked number one in customer service, due to the customer focused culture created and maintained .
- Helped revise and improve, dough production procedures and labor forecasting. this
 resulted in better labor control and less food waste.

CodeWorks Student- April 2020 - July 2020

HomeScholar - https://homescholar.herokuapp.com

Description:

As a home school teacher create lesson plans and grade student assignments with ease all while auto generating printable transcripts . Share events or tips and tricks with other users.

contributions:

Developed the front and back end for the social aspect of this application. Helped with design and plan using Figma for design, Trello for scrum and LucidChart for data relationships.

Keeper- not currently deployed

Description:

Inspired by Pinterest's boards and pins. Create keeps and store them in vaults. Users can create a keep with a name description and image and save it for themselves of share it with the world.

contributions:

Wrote the client side of this application using Vue.Js and Bootstrap. The server of this application was done utilizing .Net WebApi and dapper. Auth0 was used for authorization management.

Bug Tracker- https://track-a-bug.herokuapp.com/

Description:

Report and track bugs in your application. Update the status and make notes as the bugs are fixed or updated.

contributions:

For the client used Vue.Js and Bootstrap to style and structure the pages. For the server utilized Node.Js and MongoDb to handle server requests and handle data storage needs.